aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Vicious prisoners escaped from the Space Prison of Sargasso, and have begun their planetary galley.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
In order to protect the peace of Earth, Brave Seijin of the Space Police granted these six the brave powers of Dagwon.
지구의 평화를 지키기 위해 우주 경찰 기구의 브레이브 성인이 힘을 부여한 여섯명의 용자 다그온
And now, their new member is Gunkid!
그리고 새로운 동료는, 건키드!
A Shudder
Over the Blue Planet
푸른 별의 전율
Alien of Fear Ladonpa Seijin
Appears
공포 우주인 라돈파 성인
등장
What is... this hole?
뭐지, 이 구멍은?
What did it? Why did it dig this hole?
누구의 짓이지?
어째서 이런 구멍을…
-It's Kai.
-This is Ryu.
-카이다
-여기는 류
A big spaceship has appeared. Now tracking.
거대한 우주선이 나타났어
현재 추적중
Alright. I'll go there immediately.
알았어, 바로 갈게
What exactly is it doing?
대체 뭘 하고 있는 거지?
Stop it!
그만둬!
Damn... it's no good.
젠장… 틀렸어
Is that the spaceship?
저게 그 우주선인가?
Yeah. For some reason, it keeps digging holes.
그래, 어째서인지 커다란 구멍을 계속 파고 있어
Alright, let's find out if we can stop it or not!
좋아, 막을 수 있을지 어떨지, 해 보자
Acknowledged.
알았어
We failed again...
역시 틀렸군…
I ca- can't see anything!
아, 아무것도 보이질 않아!
Damn, did it ran away?
제길, 도망쳤나…
A planet full of feeble peace like lukewarm water.
마치 미지근한 물과 같은 나약한 평화에 가득 찬 별이다
How pathetic.
하찮기 그지없군
An unforgivable planet.
용서할 수 없는 별이야
Excuse me! Please throw the ball!
미안해요~
공 좀 집어 주세요~
Over here! Over here! Sorry about this!
여기요 여기, 미안해요~
I am sick and tired of those brats looking for happiness.
행복을 갈망하는 녀석… 정말 신물이 난다
I will make all of you bastards realize the misery I had to go through.
네놈들 모두에게 이몸이 겪은 불행을 통감케 해주마
Was that spaceship looking for something?
그 우주선이 뭔가를 찾고 있다고?
Right. It wasn't simply digging holes.
그래, 그건 단순히 구멍을 파고 있는 게 아니야
There is no explanation other than it was looking for something buried deep in the ground.
땅속 깊숙히 묻혀 있는 뭔가를 찾고 있는 거라면 납득이 가
I see.
확실히 그렇군
It looked like it didn't have the will to fight.
녀석에겐 싸울 의지가 없는 것 같고 말이야
Look at this.
이걸 봐
These are the places that the spaceship appeared and dug holes.
이곳이 어제 우주선이 나타나, 구멍을 판 곳이야
And here...
그리고 이곳이…
The place that it appeared this morning.
오늘 아침에 녀석이 나타난 곳인가….
Do you know what this line means?
이 선이 뭔지 알겠어?
-35 degrees north latitude.
-Right.
-북위 35도
-맞아
The spaceship appeared in 35 deg. N. L. two times, especially at places facing the sea.
우주선은 두번이나 북위 35도 그것도 바다를 향하고 곳에 출현하고 있어
Is this a coincidence?
이건… 우연일까?
There are two places facing the pacific ocean in 35 deg. N. L.
북위 35도상에서 태평양을 향하는 곳이 두 군데 남았어
Here, point A, and here, point B.
이 A지점과 이 B지점이야
It seems that guy couldn't find what it was looking for yet.
아마 녀석은 아직 찾고 있는 물건을 발견하지 못했을 거야
Then it'll probably appear in two other places.
그렇다면 다음엔 그 두 군데 중 한 곳을 찾을 가능성이 높겠군
That's it.
바로 그거야
Let's divide and wait for it to appear in point A and point B.
둘로 갈라져서, A지점과 B지점에서 각자 적의 출현을 기다리자
Roger. I'll go to point B.
라져, 내가 B지점으로 갈게
Please do so.
부탁해
Would it be alright even if we don't tell En and the others?
다른 애들에게 알리지 않아도 되겠어?
We're not sure about the our enemy's movements.
아직 적의 출현 양상이 분명하지 않아
For now, let's find it by us two.
당분간 우리 둘이서만 찾아보자
You're right.
그렇군
This is Ryu. No abnormalities in point B.
여기는 류, 현재 B지점은 이상 없어
I see. So is point A.
그렇군, A지점도 현재는 아무런 움직임도 없어
-Let's wait for a bit longer.
-Understood.
-조금 더 기다려 보자
-알았어
What the-?!
뭐야?!
It appeared!
나타났구나!
Damn, Dagwon again!
젠장, 또 다그온이 나타났군
I must hurry with my search.
수색을 서둘러야겠어
Shit!
아뿔싸!
How was that, Dagwon?
맛이 어떠냐, 다그온
Steam, huh...
수증기군…
What is it?
누구냐?!
You must be an alien from Sargasso.
사르갓소의 우주인이지?!
And you are Dagwon!
너는, 다그온?!
What's your objective?
네놈의 목적은 뭐지?
Why are you digging holes?
어째서 구멍을 파고 있는 거냐?!
Why, now?
글쎄… 어째서일까?
I am Ladonpa Seijin. Your fate is in my hands.
나는 라돈파 성인
너의 운명은 내 손안에 있다
What the heck are you looking for?!
네놈은 대체 뭘 찾고 있는 거지?
Did you already know I was digging holes to find something?
뭔가를 찾기 위해 구멍을 파고 있다는 걸 간파하고 있었나?
It's evident that you're devoted to searching.
이렇게나 열심히 찾고 있으니 말이야
It must be something very important.
상당히 중요한 거겠지
That's right. I might tell this only to you.
그렇군, 너에게만 알려주도록 하마
What I am looking for is called Ladonpa's box.
내가 찾고 있는 건 라돈파의 상자라 불리우는 물건이다
Ladonpa's box?
라돈파의 상자?
That's right. It is the ultimate weapon that can easily exterminate mere earthlings just by opening the lid!
그래, 일개 지구인 따위는 상자의 뚜껑을 여는 것만으로 간단히 멸망시킬 수 있는 공포의 최종 병기다!
What did you say?!
뭐라고?!
I see that Ladonpa's box is not here.
이곳에도 라돈파의 상자는 없었나보군
Then I have only one place left to search.
그렇다면, 남은 건 이제 한 곳 뿐이다
What I'm looking for must be there.
그곳에 틀림없이 내가 찾고 있는 물건이 있다
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
It's already been tens of years.
벌써 수십년 전의 옛날 일이다
Because I destroyed planets using Ladonpa's box,
나는 라돈파의 상자를 사용해서 혹성을 파괴하여
I was being chased by Space Police.
우주 경찰 기구에 쫓기고 있었다
Since I got into trouble, I had to throw this box to the Earth.
궁지에 몰린 나는 지구를 향해 라돈파의 상자를 던졌지
Because of that, I do not know where exactly the box fell.
그래서 상자가 낙하한 곳은 정확히 알 수 없었다
But it must be there in the place that I'm going right now.
하지만, 이제부터 갈 장소에는 틀림없이 있을 거야
Ladonpa's box is waiting for me deep in the dark ground.
어두운 땅속에서 라돈파의 상자는 나를 기다리고 있다
It is waiting for itself to be opened.
그 뚜껑이 열리는 순간을 말이지
Are you going to open the box?
뚜껑을 열 작정인가?!
That's right! And the Earth will cease to exist.
그래! 그걸로 지구는 끝장이야
Earthlings are going to die without an exception.
지구인은 한 놈도 빠짐없이 죽는다
The earthlings that I abhor will suffer from total destruction!
증오스럽기 그지없는 지구인은 전멸하는 거다
Why do you show hatred to the people of Earth?!
네놈은 어째서 지구인을 증오하는 거지?
What did earthlings ever do to you?!
지구인이 네놈에게 무슨 짓을 했다는 거냐?!
-Shut up!
-What?
-닥쳐라!
-뭣이?
I hate everything.
나는 질색이다
Something fun. Something peaceful. Something intimate.
즐거운 것, 평화로운 것, 사이가 좋은 것
Something bright. Something kind. Something equal!
밝은 것, 다정한 것, 평등한 것!
and something happy!
그리고 행복한 것이 말이다!
I am sick of these guys living tranquilly on a peaceful planet like yours.
너희들처럼 평화로운 별에서 안온하게 살고 있는 녀석들을 보고 있자면 신물이 난다
And I want to kill all of them.
그리고 모두 죽여버리고 싶어지지
So was that planet.
그 별도 그랬다
So was that planet! So was that planet! So was that planet!
그 별도! 그 별도! 그 별도!
I destroyed all the planets that I didn't like using Ladonpa's box.
내 마음에 들지 않는 별은 모조리 라돈파의 상자로 멸망시켰다
This Earth will suffer the same fate.
이 지구도 똑같은 운명을 맞이할 것이다
You hate peace?
평화를 증오한다고?
Yes, I do.
그래, 증오한다
I get nettle rash just by hearing that word.
그 말을 듣는 것만으로 두드러기가 날 정도다
So you destroyed numerous planets with such an insignificant reason?
그딴 이유로 수많은 별을 멸망시켜온 거냐?!
Insignificant reason?!
그딴 이유라고?!
It's more than enough for me!
내게 있어서는 충분하고도 남을 정도다!
I have the right to.
내게는 그럴 권리가 있다
What's so funny?
뭐가 우습지?
-You're one pitiful guy.
-What?!
-불쌍한 녀석이군
-뭣이라고?!
I do not know the reason of your hatred.
네 증오의 원인은 알 수 없어
Maybe you had a outrageously miserable life.
어쩌면 터무니없이 불행한 인생을 보내왔을지도 몰라
But venting your anger towards innocent people and passing the buck to them
하지만 그 화풀이를 타인을 향하고, 책임을 전가하려 하다니
aren't different from a kid nagging!
어린애가 떼쓰는 것과 다를 바 없어!
Say that again!
한 번 더 지껄여 봐라!
I will!
몇번이고 말해 주마!
You are the most childish and low criminal even in Sargasso!
네놈은 사르갓소 내에서도 유난히 유치하고도 저속한 범죄자다!
Unforgivable!
용서치 않겠다!
Persisting stubbornly ends now.
억지부리는 것도 지금 뿐이다
Look with your own eyes.
너도 그 눈으로 보거라
The look of earthlings walking toward their downfall.
지구인 놈들이 멸망해 가는 모습을…
Tell me. What exactly is Ladonpa's box?
들려다오
라돈파의 상자란 대체 뭐지?
It is a mystery of the vast space that you can't even imagine.
너는 상상조차 할 수 없는 대우주의 신비지
What is that?
그건 대체…
I see we're finally at the final place to look.
호오, 마지막 수색 지점에 도착한 것 같군
It appeared as expected.
역시 나타났군
It is there.
-있구나
-크윽!
I finally found it!
마침내 발견했다!
Dear Ladonpa's box...
라돈파의 상자여
How much I thought about the moment of opening your lid...
그 뚜껑을 열 순간을 몇번이나 감옥 안에서 꿈꾸었던가
That's Ladonpa's box!
그게 라돈파의 상자인가?!
What's your expectations about what's in the box?
이 상자 안에 무엇이 있을 거라 생각하나?
I guess you want to know.
알고 싶겠지?
I will let you know.
가르쳐 주마
The box is full of all the evil spirits.
이 상자 안에는 온갖 악한 마음이 모여 있다
-Evil spirits?
-That's right.
-악한 마음이라고?
-그래!
Anger. Hatred. Jealously. Malice.
분노, 증오, 질투, 원념
And murderous intent!
그리고 살의!
When the box opens, the released evil spirits will take over the Earth in the blink of an eye.
이 뚜껑을 연 순간 해방된 악한 마음은 순식간에 지구상을 뒤덮는다
No way...
그럴수가…
Can you think about the sight of that?
네가 그 광경을 상상할 수 있겠나?
The once peaceful planet will become hell.
평화로웠던 별도 지옥으로 변하여
There won't be any love between parents and children nor love between lovers anymore.
더 이상 부모 자식간의 온정도 연인간의 정도 없다
All the adults, children, men, and women will rage, abuse, detest, and kill each other at last.
어른도, 아이도, 남자도, 여자도 분노하고, 욕하고, 서로 증오하여 최후에는 서로 죽이는 거다
You bastard!
이자식!
After that, I'll watch the sight of earthlings slowly self-destructing themselves from the universe.
그렇게 해서 지구인 놈들이 자멸해가는 모습을 나는 우주에서 천천히 관람하도록 하겠다
Stop! Please stop!
그만둬! 제발 그만둬!
Open the hellgate!
지옥의 문이여
자, 열리거라!
Ryu!
류…!
Shadow Kunai!
섀도우 쿠나이!
You brat!
이자식!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Turbo Kai!
터보 카이
We'll stop you!
그렇게는 안돼!
We did it!
해치웠다!
That guy was nothing more than a right arm!
녀석의 정체는 오른팔 뿐이었단 말인가!
Now!
지금이다!
No!
아뿔싸!
You let your mind go! It's too late even if you realized now!
방심했구나, 하지만 이미 늦었다!
Ladonpa's box has started to work!
라돈파의 상자는 움직이기 시작했다!
Let's escape!
탈출하자!
Got it! Let's destroy the spaceship and all!
좋아, 밖에서 우주선 채로 녀석을 파괴하자!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
Shadow Shuriken!
섀도우 수리검!
Wheel Bomber!
호일 범버!
Shadow Vulcan!
섀도우 발칸!
Dagwon! It's my victory!
다그온! 나의 승리다!
No way!
그럴수가!
Light of hatred! Light of malice! Light of jealousy!
오오, 증오의 빛여!
원한의 빛이여! 질투의 빛이여!
Kill each other and self-destruct!
서로 죽이고, 자멸하거라
The peaceful Earth ends now!
평화로운 지구도 이걸로 끝장이다!
The box is now open.
상자는 열려 버렸어
What will Earth become?
지구는 어떻게 되는 걸까?
It will probably be taken over by the evil spirits.
아마 지금쯤 모두 악한 마음에 지배당했겠지
No, maybe the city already transformed to a scene of destruction and massacre.
아니, 이미 마을은 파괴와 살육의 무대로 변했을지도 몰라
No way!
그럴수가…!
Hey! Kai and Ryu!
어레, 카이와 류군요
I didn't see you in school today.
오늘은 둘 다 학교에서 못 봤는데…
Did something happen?
무슨 일 있었나요?
Did you do something?
무슨 일 있어요?
It's not right... Nothing has changed!
이상해… 아무것도 변하질 않았어
Kai, your absence has gained fame all around the school!
카이, 전 교내에 소문 쫙 퍼졌어
I heard that you were missing from every class today.
너 오늘 수업 다 빠졌다면서?
It's no good.
정말이라니까
What was chair of discipline doing, skipping all the classes?
귀신 풍기 위원장이 땡땡이라니 대체 뭐하고 있었냐?
Did you have a date?
설마 데이트~?
But still, isn't a day without aliens good?
하지만, 우주인이 나타나지 않으니까 좋구만
We can play game without any worry!
이렇게 게임을 즐길 수 있으니 말이야
What would you call this other than peace?
이걸 평화가 아니면 뭐라고 하겠냐?
The city has not changed at all. That's a relief.
마을은 평소와 마찬가지야, 다행이야
What happened?
어떻게 된 거지?
I saw Ladonpa's box being opened...
라돈파의 상자는 확실히 열렸는데…
The box must be faulty.
그 상자는 분명 망가져 있었을 거야
It didn't worked as expected.
정상적으로 작동하지 않은 거야
I see.
그렇구나…
That might be the case.
그럴지도 몰라
Kai... what do you have in mind?
카이… 무슨 생각을 하는 거야?
Is humanity a truly pure creature?
인간은 그정도로 순수한 생물일까?
Humans always do evil, big and small.
인간은 평소에도 크고 작은 악행을 저지르고 있어
Crime rates keep increasing...
범죄는 늘어만 가고…
War was never absent on Earth.
전쟁도 한 번도 이 지구상에서 사라진 적이 없어
As long as us human exist as humans,
우리 인간이 인간으로 존재하는 한
we won't be freed from evil spirits.
악한 마음으로부터 해방되는 일은 없겠지
Did Ladonpa Seijin overestimate the Earth as a peaceful planet?
라돈파 성인은 지구가 평화로운 별이라고 과대평가하고 있었다는 건가?
I see. Ladonpa's box worked as expected.
그래, 라돈파의 상자는 정상적으로 작동했어
But it didn't have an effect on us earthlings.
하지만 우리 지구인에게는 효과가 없었어
Even without Ladonpa's box,
라돈파의 상자가 없더라도
are earthlings destined to fall?
지구인은 언젠가 멸망해갈 운명이 아닐까?
You know, Kai.
하지만 말이야, 카이
We don't know our future.
미래는 알 수 없어
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
The sky is full of an aurora.
하늘에 온통 오로라가 나타났어
It started to snow and the city is frozen up.
눈이 내리기 시작해서, 마을은 얼어붙고 말아
It is that guy...
녀석이야…
Ark Seijin is trying to annihilate the Earth by freezing it!
아크 성인이 마침내 지구를 얼려서 전멸시키려 하고 있어!
At this rate, the Earth will suffer the same fate as the Sword Planet, the home planet of Lian!
이대로라면 지구는 라이안의 고향 검성과 똑같은 운명을 맞이하게 돼
We have no more time! There's nothing we can do!
시간이 이 없어! 더이상 손 쓸 도리가 없어!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! 5 Minutes before the Ice Age
다음회 용자지령 다그온
지구 빙하기 5분전
We will have to bring out the last measure!
이렇게 되면 남은 수단은 단 하나다!
5 Minutes before the Ice Age
지구 빙하기 5분전